Welcome to TeachTeam - a comprehensive teaching assistant management system
Built with React, TypeScript, and modern full-stack technologies
Let's start by launching the application with a single command
npm start automatically installs dependencies and seeds the database
The system runs two separate applications simultaneously
Main application at port 5174 for candidates and lecturers
Admin panel at port 5175 for system administration
Here's the main application homepage with clean, professional design
Users can register as candidates or lecturers with full validation
Let me sign in as a lecturer to show the review system
Dr. Smith can review applications for assigned courses only
The filtering system allows search by name, skills, and availability
Real-time search with 400ms debouncing for smooth performance
Lecturers can select candidates using checkboxes
The ranking system prevents duplicates and validates input
Comments can be added with 1000 character limit validation
Now let's look at the comprehensive analytics dashboard
Application statistics shown with interactive bar charts
Skills distribution analysis using pie charts with percentages
Availability trends show selection patterns over time
These charts use Container-Presenter architecture pattern
Clear separation between business logic and visual presentation
Now let's see the candidate experience
Signing in as Alice Johnson, a pre-created candidate
The application form supports multiple course applications
Six courses available from Python to Blockchain development
For each course, candidates choose Tutorial or Lab roles
Skills selection from comprehensive predefined list
Programming, AI, Blockchain, Web3, and more technologies
Academic credentials require minimum 10 characters
Previous experience also validated for quality
Form submission includes comprehensive client-side validation
Success confirmation shows professional user experience
My Applications page lets candidates track submission status
Now let's explore the admin panel functionality
Admin dashboard provides six core management functions
Course management with full CRUD operations
Course codes must follow COSCxxxx format
Semester format requires YYYY-S structure
Duplicate prevention for course names and codes
Lecturer assignment controls course review access
Only assigned lecturers can review course applications
Candidate management includes block and unblock functionality
Comprehensive reporting system for decision making
Selected candidates report shows rankings and assignments
Overloaded candidates report identifies excessive workloads
Unselected candidates report tracks recruitment gaps
The system includes comprehensive test coverage
Backend tests cover controllers, authentication, and validation
Frontend tests use React Testing Library
Dual API architecture: REST for main app, GraphQL for admin
MySQL database with TypeORM for entity relationships
Professional development workflow with hot reload
TeachTeam demonstrates enterprise-grade development practices
Production-ready solution for university tutor recruitment
Scalable architecture supporting growing user bases
Thank you for exploring TeachTeam's comprehensive features